Daniel Filipe Nunes Silva COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS ENGINEER SPECIALIZED IN CYBERSECURITY



PERSONALITY

Interests

Specialty Coffee

Watchmaking

Traits

Honesty Critical Thinking Enthusiasm

PERSONAL INFO

Location

Fribourg, Switzerland

Phone Number

+41 76 545 00 24

Email

danielementary@proton.me

GitHub

github.com/danielementary

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/nunessilva

ABOUT ME

I am a fresh graduate from EPFL in communication systems specialized in cybersecurity. Facing new challenges, learning modern technologies, and working on hands-on projects motivate me. I aim to enable positive change in our digital world using my skills in security and privacy.

EDUCATION

MSc in Communication Systems at EPFL

2019-2022

Strong background in cryptography, software and information security, formal verification, and interest in image processing and machine learning

BSc in Communication Systems at EPFL

2016-2019

Strong background in mathematics, information theory, algorithms, and interest in visual computing and data science

EXPERIENCE

Cryptography Intern at Nym Technologies SA SEP. 2021-MAR. 2022

Design and implement Rust applications for the Nym network leveraging attribute-based credentials and zero-knowledge proofs.

Software Developer at PROGIN SA

SUMMER 2020

Develop a dedicated construction cost estimating software in C# and the corresponding SQL database for the company.

Research Intern at Kudelski Security

SUMMER 2019

Build a proof of concept for the FENTEC project by extending FFmpeg C source code to perform motion detection on encrypted video streams.

Low-Voltage Systems Developer at EPFLRT

FEB. 2019-MAR. 2020

Integrate several sensors in EPFL's Formula Student racing car in collaboration with the different divisions to allow data acquisition.

PROJECTS

Formally Verified Prefix-Free Codes

Implement a prefix-free encoder-decoder pair in Scala and formally prove the implementation for correctness thanks to the Stainless framework.

Zero-Knowledge Circuit Evaluation with Preprocessing

Implement the ZKB++ protocol featuring KKW preprocessing, which enables privacy-preserving computations, in Go and using the Lattigo library.

Software Security Labs

Practice code audit, unit testing, and fuzzing. Play CTFs such as exploitation, reverse engineering, and forensics.

COMPETENCIES

Programming

Python, Go, Rust, C, C#, Java, SQL

Scala, Stainless, Coq

Linux, Shell Scripting, Git, Vim

Competitions

Google Hash Code 2018, 2019 and 2021

LauzHack 2018

EPFL Santa's Algorithmic Challenge 2017

Swiss Olympiad in Informatics 2016

Interpersonal Skills

Collaboration

Adaptability

Active Listening

Languages

French Native

Portuguese Native

English C1

German B2